# Jerome-Alexis Chevalier

#### PH. D. IN MACHINE LEARNING

17. rue de Gassendi. 75017 Paris

□ +33 (0)6 65 64 02 78 | **□** jerome-alexis.chevalier@inria.fr | **□** ja-che

## Summary.

I recently obtained a **PhD in machine learning** that focuses on designing inference algorithms for neuro-imaging. I have a **three-year work experience** in quantitative investment. I decided to specialize in machine learning since I am **passionate about statistical learning and coding**. Now, I would like to **take part in concrete projects** that require machine learning skills.

## Education

## Inria Paris-Saclay and Telecom ParisTech

**Paris** 

PHD CANDIDATE: STATISTICAL CONTROL OF SPARSE MODELS IN HIGH DIMENSION

2017 - 2021

- Studied and implemented many high dimensional inference algorithms to elect the most relevant solution for neuro-imaging purposes
- Tested several clustering and ensembling techniques that can combine with statistical inference and deal with data spatially structured
- Developed an inference method that achieves state-of-the-art results in neuro-imaging and additionally brings statistical guarantees
- Developed an open source Python package for high dimensional inference: HiDimStat https://ja-che.github.io/hidimstat/
- · Wrote 6 conference/journal articles including papers that focus on broad experimental validations or on theoretical developments
- · Acquired Python good practices: collaborative work with GitHub, continuous integration, unit test, etc.

#### **Universite Paris Diderot, Paris 7**

Paris

MASTER OF SCIENCE: STATISTICS, PROBABILITY AND DATA SCIENCE (M2MO, EX-DEA LAURE ELIE)

2016 - 2017

• Machine Learning, Datamining, Probability, Statistics, Stochastic Calculus, Python, C++

Essec Busisness School Paris

Advanced Master: Financial Techniques 2013 - 2014

ENSEIRB-MATMECA Bordeaux

MASTER OF ENGINEERING: MATHEMATICAL MODELING AND MECHANICS 2010 - 2013

Lycee Michel Montaigne

Bordeaux

Preparatory Class: Mathematics and Physics 2008 - 2010

## **Publications**

MICCAI 2018: Chevalier, J.A., Salmon, J., Thirion, B.: Statistical inference with ensemble of clustered desparsified lasso

IPMI 2019: Chevalier, J.A., Nguyen, B., Thirion, B.: ECKO: Ensemble of clustered knockoffs for robust multivariate inference on MRI data

ICML 2020: Nguyen, B., Chevalier, J.A., Thirion, B., Arlot, S.: Aggregation of Multiple Knockoffs

**NeurIPS 2020:** Chevalier, Gramfort, Salmon, Thirion: Statistical control for spatio-temporal MEG/EEG source imaging with d-MTLasso **NeuroImage Journal 2021:** Chevalier, Nguyen, Varoquaux, Salmon, Thirion: Decoding with confidence: Statistical control on decoder maps **Submitted to a statistical journal:** Chevalier, Nguyen, Thirion, Salmon: Spatially relaxed inference on high-dimensional linear models

## **Experience**

Inria Paris-Saclay Paris

DOCTORAL CODING MISSION Sep. 2018 - Sep. 2019

• Contributed to Nilearn open source ML library designed for neuro-imaging in Python which involves 100+ contributors / 1000+ users

### **Amundi Alternative Investments**

London

QUANTITATIVE ANALYST IN ALTERNATIVE INVESTMENTS

Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2016

Nov. 2014 - Jun. 2015

Apr. 2014 - Oct. 2014

- · Developed and maintained a fund ranking algorithm to select the 100 "best" hedge funds among the 1000+ referenced funds
- · Contributed to the monthly allocation strategy outlooks working closely with three different teams: Equity, Fixed Income, Macro

#### **BNP Paribas Investments Partners - THEAM**

Paris

• Managed a range of CPPI lifecycle funds corresponding to more than 1 billion Euros of assets under management

· Completed the full investment process on a day-to-day basis including the risky asset allocation and the interest rate hedging

#### **Oddo & Cie - Oddo Asset Management**

Paris

QUANTITATIVE INVESTMENT ANALYST

Built investment style indexes and smart beta strategies to monitor market trends and develop new funds

## Skills

**Programming:** Python (Scikit-Learn, Scipy, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn), R, C++, Matlab

Tools: Atom, Latex, Git, Jupyter notebooks, Linux, GitHub CI, Travis CI, PyPI

Languages: French (native), English (fluent), Spanish (intermediate)

SEPTEMBER 15, 2021 JEROME- ALEXIS CHEVALIER · RESUME